# Raja

#### **Technical Architect**



Chennai, TN, 603103

Accomplished Technical Architect offering 15 years' experience in comprehensive design and development of infrastructure and architecture for software projects. Attentive collaborator and communicator from project conception to completion. Creative in devising solutions to improve business operations and meet clients' technical needs. Seasoned team leader possessing the technical and interpersonal skills to provide exceptional project deliverables.



#### **Skills**

- Systems Engineering
- Communicating with clients
- Proficient in NodeJs, Java
- Conceptualizing development projects
- Cloud services AWS
- Software Architecture
- Solution prototypes
- **Technical Analysis**
- Experience in Travel and Transportation Domain



# **Work History**

#### 2019-10 - Current

#### **AWS Solution Architect**

Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai, Tamilnadu

- Managed use of various types of databases and configured, installed and upgraded new ones.
- Worked closely with customers, internal staff and other stakeholders to determine planning, implementation and integration of system-oriented projects.
- Managed and monitored all installed systems for highest level of availability.
- Wrote and maintained custom scripts to increase system efficiency and performance time.
- Installed, configured, tested and maintained operating systems,

2011-12 - 2016-10

2010-06 - 2011-11

2001-06 - 2004-05

- application software and system management tools.
- Led a technical team in delivery of ecommerce project, resulting in increased digital foot print, sales for the company.

#### Technical Lead

Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai, Tamilnadu

- Organized system infrastructure documentation and operating procedures, strengthening controls and enhancing overall performance.
- Evaluated and adopted new technologies to address changing industry needs.
- Integrated automation into monitoring and security measures to reduce required employee attention.
- Offered input on technical and platform-related strategic planning initiatives, prioritizing overarching business goals.
- Designed and monitored required support structure needed to confirm stable and scalable application rollouts.
- Mentored junior team members, providing educational expertise on technical, business and domain concepts.

#### **Education**

## **Bachelor of Science: Computer Science**

Bharathidasan University

# **Accomplishments**

TCS Beyond Excellence Award for contribution towards project release.

## **Certifications**

Sun Certified Java Programmer



Foundation Certification in Travel and Transportation



It was indeed a great pleasure working with Vijay as an IT technical architect partner at Panalpina, in a large-scale digitalization project led by me. Vijay is an amazing professional, who brings all of the skills and expertise in software architecture and programming. Vijay's contribution to our digital products led to the expansion of digital footprint of our company. I'm hopeful he'll deliver ever more to other institutions as well.

# **Gianluca Lupo - Senior Cloud Application Architect presso Amazon Web Services (AWS)**

I've had the pleasure of working with Vijay for the past 1.5 years. Vijay has a very strong work ethic and great analytical and problem solving skills. His hands-on approach and strong motivation helped to deliver software solutions in stressful and dynamic context. Open to receive feedbacks in constructive way, with his positive attitude Vijay is an excellent team player and it is a pleasure to work with.

#### Nenad Mijatovic - Solution Architect, Director at Julius Baer

Enthusiasm, Analytical Skills are the qualities that comes to mind when I think about Vijay. I've had the pleasure of knowing Vijay for 1 year, during which I worked with him in Panalpina while building an ecommerce portal. Above all, I was impressed with Vijay's ability to put things to perspective, attention to detail. And, of course, his knack of addressing the core of the problem. Vijay would be a true asset for any positions requiring Data Modeling and API Design and comes with my heartfelt recommendation.



#### **Software**

- Languages (Javascript, T-SQL, Java, Node JS)
- AWS (AWS Lambda, Amazon ECS Fargate, Amazon Aurora Serverless DB, AWS SNS, AWS SQS, Cloudwatch)
- Databases (PostgreSQL 9.6, SQL Server 2005, DB2, Oracle 10g, MySQL 5.0)
- Tools (Eclipse, Tortoise SVN, Git, Bitbucket, Team Foundation, HP Quality Center).
- Platforms (Windows 10, RHEL, Suse Linux)
- Servers (Apache Tomcat, Oracle 10g Application Server, IBM WebSphere, Jboss )